Guide to the G. William Skinner papers, 1948-1988, 1951-1958 (bulk).
Skinner, G. William papers
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
G. William Skinner papers, 1948-1988, 1951-1958 (bulk).
14-27-2778
G. William(George William), Skinner 1925-2008.
24.6 cubic ft.
Research Materials
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Field materials from Thailand and Indonesia, notes, and printouts of G. William Skinner.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
G. William Skinner was born in Oakland, California, in 1925. From 1942-43, he attended Deeps Springs College (California), then joined the Navy V-12 Program at Missouri Valley College for two years before completing 18 months of instruction in Chinese at the U.S. Navy Oriental Language School at the University of Colorado. He then completed his Bachelor's degree at Cornell University (1946-47) with Distinction in Far Eastern Studies.
Skinner then went on to pursue doctoral studies in anthropology at Cornell University, with an interest in market towns and their regions in China. He began fieldwork at Gaodianzi, near Chengdu, Sichuan Province, in 1949, but this was disrupted when the Communists won the civil war in China. Skinner was forced to leave his fieldsite in January, 1950, and was confined to Chengdu until August, when he was allowed to leave China.
With the closing of China, Skinner shifted his attention to Chinese communities in Southeast Asia, with an initial field survey conducted in 1950. This was followed by a doctoral project on the Chinese of Thailand, completed in 1954 while he was also Field Director of the Cornell Southeast Asia Program in Bangkok (1951-55). Subsequently, he joined the Cornell Modern Indonesia Project as a Research Associate, and was in Indonesia from 1956-58 to conduct research on the Chinese of Indonesia and oversee related projects.
From 1958-60, Skinner was Assistant Professor of Sociology at Columbia University, before returning to Cornell as Associate Professor of Anthropology (1960-62) and then Professor of Anthropology (1962-65). It was during this time (1964-65) that he published his much celebrated "Marketing and Social Structure in Rural China" as three articles in successive issues of the Journal of Asian Studies, which established him as a preeminent scholar of China.
Subsequently, Skinner was appointed Professor of Anthropology at Stanford University (1965-89) and the University of California, Davis (1990-2005). He was also President of the Association of Asian Studies in 1983. Besides being noted as an eminent anthropologist of China, Skinner was best known for his work on the dynamics of social structure and space, which he applied to the study of China, Japan and France using geographic information system techniques. His work on hierarchical regional systems was also instrumental in the shaping of the China Historical Geographic Information System, which provides a database of populated places and historical administrative units throughout Chinese history.
The Skinner papers deposited with Cornell University mainly come from the Southeast Asia phase of his career. These include research materials collected for his seminal works on the Chinese of Thailand and Indonesia. These materials not only informed Skinner's understanding of Chinese culture and kinship dynamics, but also demonstrated his early interest in mapping sociological data onto geographical frameworks.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Research files, notes, and printouts of G. William Skinner.
Notes on the Chinese in Thailand and Indonesia.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Skinner, G. William1925-2008.
Subjects:
Chinese--Indonesia; Chinese--Thailand.; Cornell University--Faculty.
Places:
Thailand.; Indonesia.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
SERIES LIST
Series I. 1948, Graduate Study
As a graduate student with the Department of Anthropology at Cornell, Skinner participated in a week-long field research project at Cundiyo, New Mexico. Included are his field materials, field notes and report.
Box: 1
Series II. 1950, Indonesia
Skinner originally began his PhD fieldwork in Chengdu, China. But when the People’s Liberation Army won the civil war in Mainland China, Skinner had to discontinue his research. Before he returned to Cornell, he went on a field survey of Southeast Asia to gain an overview of the Chinese communities of the region, which resulted in the publication of Report on the Chinese in Southeast Asia, December 1950 (1951). Included are notes of his interviews in Jakarta and Surabaya during this period.
Box: 2
Series III. 1951-1955, Thailand
Skinner served as Field Director of the Cornell Southeast Asia Program, directing the Cornell Research Center in Bangkok, Thailand, where he also carried out field research on the Chinese of Thailand. This led to the publication of Chinese Society in Thailand: An Analytical History (1957) and Leadership and Power in the Chinese Community of Thailand (1958). The materials include demographic data, translations of Chinese articles, notes on various forms of Chinese organizations, interviews with Chinese leaders, correspondences, analysis of the Chinese leadership structure, press clippings and field notes.
Boxes: 1-4
Series IV. 1956-1958, Indonesia
Under the auspices of the Cornell Modern Indonesia Project, Skinner conducted and directed field research in Java and West Kalimantan, focusing on the Chinese minority. In the course of his research, Skinner collected demographic, historical and ethnographic data on the Chinese. In addition, he also oversaw various projects in Tanggerang, Purwokerto and Bangka.
Boxes: 2, 4-7
Series V. 1957-1962, 1957 Survey and Early Analysis
In April 1957, Skinner conducted a landmark survey with 1,785 high school students of Chinese and indigenous Indonesian descent in Jakarta. This resulted in an unpublished manuscript entitled “Communism and Chinese Culture in Indonesia: The Political Dynamics of Overseas Chinese Youth.” Included are administrative notes related to the mechanics of the survey, the original survey questionnaires, coding keys and notes, and various draft manuscripts.
Boxes: 7-11
Series VI. 1963-1988, Sibling Status and Statistical Analysis
Through these years, Skinner revisited the 1957 survey data many times, focusing his efforts on the dynamics of sibling position. Included are grant proposals, various notes concerning statistical analysis of the data and comments on students’ papers related to the study of sibling position.
Boxes: 11-13
Series VII. 1963-1988, Printouts
Statistical analysis printouts run between 1963 and 1988
Boxes: 14-18
CONTAINER LIST
- Valedictory Address, Chinese, KY 1-2, Navy School of Oriental Languages, September 1, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 0)
- Series I. 1948, Graduate Study
  - Cundiyo (New Mexico) Fieldnotes, Skinner’s field research as a graduate student at Cornell (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Notes on Elizardo, Jose Dolores and Fidel, Grand Tour, Emiliano V. Canuto, Noberto (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Notes on Elizardo, Tour, 9/11/1948 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - 1948-9-11(2), 9/11/1948 (Box 1, Folder 1)
      Abstract of water facilities docket
    - Notes on Elizardo, Canuto, maps of tracts and owners, 9/12/1948 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Notes on Elizardo, Luis, map of Cundiyo, 9/13/1948 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - List of households (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Vigil kinship charts, 9/14/1948 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - The Recent History of Land Ownership in Cundiyo, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Cundiyo (Other Field Materials) (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Photos, Cudiyo, New Mexico, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Loose Materials and Reports, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - "Spanish Americans in the Southwest and the War Effort", 8/18/1942 (Box 1, Folder 2)
      Report No. 24, Special Services Division, Bureau of Intelligence, Office of War Information; Confidential; 18 pp.
    - "Spanish-Americans in the Southwest and the War Effort: Recommendations", 8/18/1942 (Box 1, Folder 2)
      Special Services Division, Bureau of Intelligence, Office of War Information; 5 pp.
    - "An Evaluation of Media for Reaching the Spanish-Americans of the Southwest", 8/19/1942 (Box 1, Folder 2)
      Report No. 23a, Special Services Division, Bureau of Intelligence, Office of War Information; Confidential; 10 pp.
    - "War Attitudes of the Spanish-Speaking People in the Southwest", 8/11/1942 (Box 1, Folder 2)
      Special Report No. 19, Division of Surveys, Bureau of Intelligence, Office of War Information; Confidential; 13 pp.
  - Cundiyo Research Manuscripts (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - "The Kinship System of the Spanish-Americans of New Mexico", 1948 December (Box 1, Folder 3)
      Paper submitted for "Sociology & Anthropology 431", Cornell University; 26 pp.
    - "Cundiyo, New Mexico: A Report on a Week’s Fieldwork in a Spanish-American Village during September, 1948", 1948 November (Box 1, Folder 3)
      41 pp.
    - "Draft" of Cundiyo Fieldwork Report (Box 1, Folder 3)
      31 pp.
- Series II. 1950, Indonesia
  - Jakarta & Surabaya Interviews, Nov 1950 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Interview - Bob Rinden, US Embassy, 11/6/1950 (Box 2, Folder 27)
      Jakarta
    - Interview - Charles Cross, USIS, 11/6/1950 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Interview - Hsieh Shan-ts’ai, CAN correspondent, 11/7/1950 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Interview - Dr Meijer, Sinological Institute, University of Indonesia, 11/7/1950 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Visit to Chung Hua Hui Kuan School, 11/8/1950 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Interview - Ang Jan Goan, Editor, Sin Po, 11/9/1950 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Interview - Dr Kator, Economics Section, Dutch High Commissioner’s Office, 11/9-10/1950 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Interview - Loa Sek Hie, 11/10/1950 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Interview - Kwee Kek Beng, Peranakan businessman, 11/10/1950 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Interview - Mr. Kao, Manager, Bank of China, Jakarta, 11/10/1950 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Interivew - Dr Tan Eng Oen, accountant, 11/11/1950 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Interview - James Elliot, USIS, 11/13/1950 (Box 2, Folder 27)
      Surabaya
    - Interview - Tan Kwat Po (editor) & The Ping Oen (director), Pewarta Surabaia, 11/13/1950 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Interview - Goh Tjing Hok & Chan Ping Hung, 11/13/1950 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Visit to in Kuang School, Chung Hua School and Lien Ho School, 11/13/1950 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Interview - Yeh Li-k’ang (Yap Li Keng), director, Tsing Kuang Daily Press, 11/14/1950 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Interview - Hsieh Kuo-chung, chairman, Chung Hua Tsung Hui, 11/14/1950 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Interview - Tan Boen Aan, Member of Parliament from Surabaia, 11/14/1950 (Box 2, Folder 27)
- Series III. 1951-1955, Thailand
  - Bibliographies (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Population statistics and estimates (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Lecture notes (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Hsieh: Thailand Gazetteer Translations (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Thai Manuscript on Chinese (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Notes - History (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Notes - Education (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Notes - Industry and Commerce (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Notes - Chinese Chamber of Commerce (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Notes - Teochew Association (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Notes - Hakka Association (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Notes - Cantonese Association (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Notes - T’ung Hsiang Hui (Clan Associations) (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Notes - Gold and Jewelry Merchants Association (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Notes - Charity, Medical, Religious Organizations (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Notes - Rice Merchants (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Notes - Ch’ao-Chou Monthly (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Notes - Miscellaneous I (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Notes - Miscellaneous II (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Chinese leaders, basic (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Chinese Leaders - Reference File (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Leader Interviews I (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Leader Interviews II (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Leader Interviews III (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Leader Interviews IV (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Leader Interviews - Miscellaneous I (1951-10-1 to 1952-7-22) (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Leader Interviews - Miscellaneous II (1952-7-23 to 1953-1-5) (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Correspondence - J.T. Peng (1953-1954) (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Analysis - Structure Analysis 1952 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Analysis - Leader Rankings 1955 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Analysis - 1955 Structure 5-Man Worksheets and 1952-55 Comparison (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Analysis - Leaders Political Analysis 1955 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Analysis - 1952 Power Structure (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Analysis - Evaluation of Chinese Leaders (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Analysis - 1955 Structure (Worksheets: General and 4-Man Structure) (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Data - Population and Migration Worksheets (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Data - Cities and Towns (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Data - Population (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Data - Press Clippings (1951-1952) (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Data - Chinese Associations Officers Lists 1955 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Data - Master List of Bangkok Chinese (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Data - Chinese Migration between Thailand and China (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Data - Business Associations I (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Data - Business Associations II (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Data - Other Business Associations (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Data - Additions to Leader File Cards (April - June 1955) (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Data - Miscellaneous (Leaders) (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Fieldnotes - Clan Associations (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Fieldnotes - Chinese Schools (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Fieldnotes - Other Associations (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Fieldnotes - Charity, Medical, Religious Organizations (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Fieldnotes - Schools (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Fieldnotes - Upcountry Trips Summaries (1954-1955) (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Fieldnotes - Miscellaneous (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Thailand data cards (Box 3)
  - Thailand data cards (Box 4)
- Series IV. 1956-1958, Indonesia
  - Jakarta Assistants Records, 1956-1959 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    Correspondence and records concerning research assistants in Indonesia
  - Indonesia Personal References and Contacts, Circa 1956-1957 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    Name cards, address books, introduction letters etc.
  - Willmott - Correspondence, Letters between G. William Skinner and Donald E. Willmott, 1954-1957 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    1954-8-2 (Skinner); 1954-8-26 (Willmott); 1954-9-22 (Willmott); 1954-9-27 (Skinner); 1954-11-20 (Willmott); 1954-12-1 (Willmott); 1954-12-11 (Skinner); 1955-1-7 (Willmott); 1955-1-12 (Skinner); 1955-3-14 (Skinner); 1955-3-27 (Willmott); 1955-4-1 (Skinner); 1955-4-25 (Willmott); 1956-1-12 (Willmott); 1956-5-21 (Willmott); 1956-6-10 (Skinner); 1956-7-5 (Willmott); 1956-9-14 (Skinner); 1956-10-1 (Willmott); 1956-11-12 (Skinner); 1956-11-18 (Skinner); 1957-2-9 (Skinner); 1957-3-7 (Willmott); 1957-5-19 (Skinner); 1957-8-15 (Willmott); 1957-10-31 (Willmott); 1957-11-19 (Skinner).
  - Willmott - Interviews, Fieldnotes, Reports (1954-1955) (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - "Report on Mixed Marriages in Semarang Municipality, 1953", Circa 1954 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - "First Quarterly Report, July 1954", 1954 July (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - "Project Report", 4/14/1955 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - "Project Report", 7/26/1955 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Interview: Information on the "Star Weekly", 5/21/1954 (Box 2, Folder 31)
      Mr. Auwjong Peng Koen, Chief Editor, "Star Weekly"; Tan Tjoei Hoek, Assistant Editor; p. 1
    - Interview: Place of women and women’s organisations, 5/24/1954 (Box 2, Folder 31)
      Herawati Diah, editor, "Merdeka" magazine, "Keluarga"; pp. 2-3
    - Interview: BUPBA - Department of Minorities, 5/24/1954 (Box 2, Folder 31)
      Soewahjo, Department Head; pp. 4-5
    - Interview: Peranakan Party Politics & Aspirations, 5/30/1954 (Box 2, Folder 31)
      Dr Oei Oe Ang; pp. 6-7
    - Interview: Courtship and Marriage Arrangement, 6/5/1954 (Box 2, Folder 31)
      pp. 8-9
    - Interview: Arrangement of Marriages in one Family, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 31)
      p. 10
    - Interview: National Party Politics & the Chinese, 6/11/1954 (Box 2, Folder 31)
      Subadio Sastrosatomo, PSI leader; pp. 11-12
    - Interview: Student Activities, 7/15/1954 (Box 2, Folder 31)
      Kismadi; pp. 13-15
    - Interview: Case study_S, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 31)
      Lawyer; pp. 16-17
    - Interview: Figures on Chinese students, 7/13/1954 (Box 2, Folder 31)
      Oey Giok Po, Keng Po editorial staff; p. 18
    - Interview: Background, 7/20/1954 (Box 2, Folder 31)
      Nio Joe Lan; p. 19
    - Interview with Mrs. Maria Ulfah Santoso, 7/18/1954 (Box 2, Folder 31)
      Secretary to Prime Minister, former Minister of Social Affairs, Director of Kongres Wanita Indonesia; pp. 20-23. (written up 1954-7-20)
    - Notes on Two Schools in Jakarta, 7/22-23/1954 (Box 2, Folder 31)
      Tiong Hoa Hwee Koan "Pah-Hua" school; Chung Hua High School; p. 24
    - Interview: Chinese Women’s Organizations, 7/23/1954 (Box 2, Folder 31)
      Mrs. Oei Hien Tjiang; pp. 25-26
    - Interview: Chinese University Students Association, 7/23/1954 (Box 2, Folder 31)
      Kho Han Tiong, Chairman, Djakarta branch of Ta Hsueh Hsueh Sheng Hui; pp. 27-28
    - Interview: Students Organizations, 7/14/1954 (Box 2, Folder 31)
      Ahmad Dahlan Ranuwihardjo, former president of Persatuan Perhimpunan Mahasiswa Indonesia; p. 29
    - Notes: Background, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 31)
      Covers the issues of "return migration" to China, KMT circles and newspapers; p. 30
    - Notes: Indonesian Youth Organization, PDI, 8/7-11/1954 (Box 2, Folder 31)
      Pemuda Demokrat Indonesia; pp. 31-32
    - Interview: Chinese Women’s Organization, etc., 8/18/1954 (Box 2, Folder 31)
      Mrs. Chung Kim Yan, head of Fu Nu Hui, active since 1931; pp. 33-34
    - Notes: King Hoo Ping Celebration, 8/22/1954 (Box 2, Folder 31)
      pp. 35-36
    - Notes: King Hoo Ping around town, 8/23/1954 (Box 2, Folder 31)
      pp. 37-38
    - Interview: History of Semarang Chinese, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 31)
      Liem Thian Joe, author of Riwajat Semarang; pp. 39-41
    - Interview: Semarang Chinese Society, 9/10/1954 (Box 2, Folder 31)
      Liem Ek Hian; p. 42
    - Notes: Personal & General, 10/23-24/1954 (Box 2, Folder 31)
      pp. 43-46
    - Notes: Wedding, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 31)
      pp. 47-50
    - Personal notes, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 31)
      pp. 51-54
    - Notes on terminology: Totok & Peranakan, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 31)
      p. 55
  - Willmott - Questionnaire (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - "Draft Questionnaire", Circa 1954 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - "Questionnaire on Family Life", Circa 1954 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - "Marginal distribution of replies to questionnaire items", Circa 1954 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - "Tanja-Djawab Tentang Kehidupan Keluarga", Circa 1954 (Box 2, Folder 32)
      Questionnaire on Family Life (Indonesian version)
    - 家庭生活的考察问题 [Chinese characters], Circa 1954 (Box 2, Folder 32)
      Questionnaire on Family Life (Chinese version)
    - "Laporan: Daripada Penjelidikan Tentang Kehidupan Keluarga Peladjar2 Djawa Tengah", Circa 1954 (Box 2, Folder 32)
      Report - From Study on Family Life in Central Java
    - Loose notes, Circa 1954 (Box 2, Folder 32)
      "Questions about towns outside Semarang"; etc
  - Jakarta Family Survey, Loose notes, data, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Tanggerang Survey, 1956-9 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - "Results of a Social Survey in Kabupaten Tanggerang", 1956-9 (Box 5, Folder 1)
      3 copies; 11 pp.
    - "Draft Questionnaire", 1959-9 (Box 5, Folder 1)
      3 pp.
  - Tanggerang Fieldnotes, 1957-1958 (Oei Bie Ing), 1957-58 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Loose leaf fieldnotes, 1957-58 (Box 5, Folder 2)
      Handwritten in pencil; 3 stacks of 59 pp., 32 pp. and 42 pp.
    - "Malam perkawinan pertama", n.d. (Box 5, Folder 2)
      7 pp.
    - Information from Phoa Tjin Houw, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - "Agriculture" and other notes, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 2)
      5 pp.
    - List of Chinese families, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - "Daftar Laporan Djiwa manusia dlm Kabupaten Tanggerang Tahun 1957", 1957 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Loose notes, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 2)
      Demographic data of Ketjamatan Telukmaga
  - Tanggerang Survey Notes (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Tabulation Coding - Tanggerang Survey, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Loose notes, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Tanggerang Study - Original Questionnaires I (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Tanggerang survey (actual questionnaire sample), n.d. (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Actual Questionnaires, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Tanggerang Study - Original Questionnaires II, Actual Questionnaires, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Bangka - Fieldnotes, Statistics & Materials (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Skinner notebook (fieldnotes), n.d. (Box 5, Folder 6)
      Probably 1956.
    - Berita Baperki (1957-11-15), 11/15/1957 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Government & Politics, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 6)
      With documents from various political parties and organizations, and election results
    - Tin mining, 1956-57 (Box 5, Folder 6)
      List of tin mining contractors
    - Chinese education, 1957, 1958 (Box 5, Folder 6)
      With staff and students information for Chung Hwa Elementary School; paper by Tan Fay Tjhion (Blinju, 20 March 1958).
    - Business and associations, 1958 (Box 5, Folder 6)
      Includes list of shops and businesses; Zhonghua Shanghui members list (1958); Zhonghua Huiguan Committee (1955)
    - Demographic data, 1956-1958 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Temple Materials, Circa 1957 (Box 5, Folder 6)
      Temple inscriptions; talisman (with reference to Tan Fay Tjhion’s fieldnotes); probably collected by Tan Fay Tjhion during his fieldwork at Blinju, Bangka, in 1957.
    - Miscellaneous, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 6)
      One page on "Relationship with the ancestors"
  - Bangka - Code Index to Tan Fieldnotes (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Bangka fieldnotes code index (subject), n.d. (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Bangka fieldnotes code index (people), n.d. (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Coding Sheet, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Bangka Report (Draft Manuscript), Manuscript by Tan Fay Tjhion, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 8)
    84 pp.
  - Bangka - Maps (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Map - Bangka (Box 5, Folder 9)
      Hand-drawn colored replicate of map dated 1845-1846
    - Maps - Blinju (Box 5, Folder 8)
      Photocopy of Dutch maps
  - Bangka - Tan Fay Tjhion fieldnotes (pp. 1-151), pp. 1-151, 4/14/1957-5/14/1957 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Bangka - Tan Fay Tjhion fieldnotes (pp. 152-311), pp. 152 - 311, 5/15/1957-7/7/1957 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Bangka - Tan Fay Tjhion fieldnotes (pp. 312-458), pp. 312 - 458, 7/3/1957-9/5/1957 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Bangka - Tan Fay Tjhion fieldnotes (pp. 459-600), pp. 459 - 600, 9/6/1957-10/14/1957 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Bangka - Tan Fay Tjhion fieldnotes (pp. 601-742), pp. 601 -742, 10/14/1957-11/21/1957 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Bangka - Tan Fay Tjhion fieldnotes (pp.743-899), pp. 743 -899, 11/23/1957-1/31/1958 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Bangka - Tan Fay Tjhion fieldnotes (pp. 900-1065), pp. 900 - 1065, 2/1/1958-3/27/1958 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - West Kalimantan: Reading Notes and Translations (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Handleiding bij de beoefening der land- en volkenkunde van Nederlandsch Oost-Indie¨, Vol. II, Chapter 2, parts, 1864? (Box 5, Folder 17)
      Translated from Dutch; 8 pp. Document has date on it of 1864, but according to Leiden University catalog, 1882-1884
    - "The Great Republican System of ‘Lan Fang’ [The History of the "Republic" founded by Lo Fang-pai in West Borneo (1777-1886)], Hua Ch’iao Hsin Yü (Combined Edition), Issue No. 4, June 1, 1953, pp. 24-26, by Hsia Min, 1953 (Box 5, Folder 17)
      Written in Bangkok, May, 1953; translated from Chinese; 6 pp.
    - Extracts from "Sketch of Montrado in 1861", Tijdschrift voor Indische Taal-, Land- en Volkenkunde, 1864 - Deel Xiii, 4e serie, deel IV, by M. von Faber, 1864 (Box 5, Folder 17)
      Translated from Dutch by LKG; 19 pp.